Muhammad ALJUNIED

FREELANCE DEVELOPER

Mobile: +65 9380 8439

Email: muhammadaliunied@u.nus.edu

Skype: muhammadaljunied

URL: muhammadaljunied.github.io



Personal Statement

Internship Objective

I am seeking a 1-year long internship in a company (preferably in a start-up) as a Software Developer. My time as an undergraduate has sparked my interest in hardware development. Despite my limited knowledge in the area, working on a product like a wearable would be an eye-opening experience and I am more than willing to learn the ropes. I hope to develop skills in web development as well as UI/UX and become an honest asset to your company. As an individual, I am a forward thinking and naturally passionate, which others may find inspiring when working as a team.

About me

Growing up, I found computers fascinating because you could write code to make it do your bidding. I was mainly inspired by my father who wrote programs to help me with my multiplication tables and practicing my spelling in his own take of an educational "game". I like solving problems with code. I value well written code and tend to view it as a work of art. I appreciate the makings of well-designed applications in terms of UI/UX because that is the front that users see and experience. The combination of both is always the goal. I am a user centric developer who strives to create the best with as little compromises as possible.

Work Experiences/Projects

Most of the projects I have worked on to date was best solved using the .NET platform. Some notable project's I worked on includes a Cheque Printing solution for a non-profit organization, several solutions for Tagronauts, an Instagram printing service, as well as a proof of concept for a student investigating the benefits of consolidating building management resources into a central location, in an attempt break into the Building Management sector by solving administrative problems plaguing the industry. I then embarked on a second internship at LOKAL*SOCIAL, a startup in Jakarta. In between projects, I would make websites for clients, mostly static sites or landing pages.

Following the internship, I served my compulsory National Service as a Police Officer. In those 2 years, I solved administrative problems that were oftentimes repetitive and tedious. I automated the creation of forms, streamlined hiring and medical processes using Excel VBA among the many projects assigned to me. These required me to think in terms of improving productivity and potential to save man-hours. I made it a point to meet the likely users of the script and had them walk me through a typical day of work. I then modeled their workflow and identified areas that can be streamlined. My solutions impacted multiple departments across the Police Force as well as the Civil Defense (Fire Department).

Some ongoing projects I work on during my free time include a file transmitter for DSLRs using a Raspberry Pi and an Administrative solution as well as a database migration for an Automobile Workshop.

I hope this gives you a little insight into the character that I am and I hope to hear from you soon.

Best Regards, Muhammad ALJUNIED

Education

Aug 2016 - Present National University of Singapore

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (HONOURS) IN COMPUTER
ENGINEERING
(Course details in Appendix A)

Temasek Polytechnic
DIPLOMA WITH MERIT, INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Singapore

Work Experience

SEP 2014 - DEC 2017 Tagronauts

Singapore

DEVELOPER/MANAGER

Tagronauts is an On-Site Photo Printing start-up that delivers the highest throughput of photos printed by accelerating the printing process using software and automation.

- Designed and deployed software for client events
- Develop MS Word Macros to improve efficiency of operations.
- Train and enforce service standards when engaging parttimers.

DEC 2014 - NOV 2015

Police National Service Department STAFF ASSISTANT (PLANNING DIVISION)

Singapore

Served as the Staff Assistant to the Assistant Director of the Planning Division and Planning Officer (Police).

- Reviewed and updated 3 Standard Operating Procedures for National Service Police Officers.
- Developed automation macros to improve operational efficiency of various divisions.

JAN 2014 - DEC 2014

Ministry of Home Affairs **EXCEL DEVELOPER (HUMAN TRANSFORMATION OFFICE)**

Singapore

National Service at the Ministry of Home Affairs under the Home Team's Flag (Police).

- Developed Excel automation to streamline existing business processes.
- Developed and deployed 20 projects across several law enforcement agencies.
- Headed data consolidation, processing and filtration for records dating 10 years.

SEP 2013 - NOV 2013 OCT 2012 - JAN 2013

LOKAL*SOCIAL

Jakarta

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

LOKAL*SOCIAL was a start-up in Jakarta that aimed to break into the food listing business with plans to pioneer restaurant bookings in the Jakarta.

- Designed and developed a native Android application on an older Android API release to maximise phone compatibility.
- Conducted testing in locations of high human traffic to measure overall data usage and speed.
- Executed marketing campaigns at Universities to garner users.

Scholastic Achievements/Extracurricular Activities

APR 2013	Anugerah Mendaki 2013 AWARD RECEIPIENT	Singapore
	Bursary for Academic Excellence (Polytechnic/Diploma)	
APR 2011 – JUN 2013	Microsoft Student Partner (MSP)	Singapore
	TECHNICAL REPRESENTATIVE	
	 Conducted a course on Azure Cloud Service with 120 participants. 	
	 The course covered deployment of ASP.NET Applications Azure. 	
	 Provided technical support up to three weeks after. 	
APR 2012 - APR 2013	Temasek Polytechnic Directors List AWARD RECEIPIENT	Singapore
	 Top 10% of the cohort for AY 11/12 and AY 12/13 	

Skill Sets & Proficiency

Programming	Java C C++ C# XAML VB VBA	Intermediate Basic Basic Proficient Intermediate Proficient Proficient
Web	HTML, CSS PHP Javascript	Basic Basic Basic
Database	MySQL MSSQL	Intermediate Intermediate
Hardware Design	Verilog Vivado 2016	Basic Basic
Office	MS Word/Powerpoint/Access + VBA MS Excel + VBA	Intermediate/Basic Intermediate/Proficient
Multimedia	Corel Photopaint x5 Adobe Photoshop CC	Basic Intermediate

Language Proficiency

Spoken	English – fluent; Malay – Basic
Written	English – competent; Malay– Basic

APPENDIX A

Degree: Bachelor of Engineering (Honours) in Computer Engineering

Course Description (List of relevant modules)	Status
Introduction to Computer Engineering	Completed
Data Structures and Algorithms I	Completed
Introductory Mathematics	Completed
Fundamentals of Physics II	Completed
Electrical Engineering	Completed
Critical Thinking And Writing	Completed
Introductory Mathematics	Completed
Discrete Structures	In-progress
Mathematics I	In-progress
Digital Fundamentals	In-progress
Electronic Circuits	In-progress
Asking Questions	In-progress